自分にはもっと自由があってもいい—
Do you think it’s about time
you had more freedom?
You may think you’re ready
to be treated as an adult,
もう十分大人だ と思っていますか？
but do your parents agree?
でも 親はそう思っているでしょうか？
もっと自由があっても大丈夫なことを
親に証明してきましたか？
Have you proven to them
that you can handle more freedom?
You see, if you want more freedom,
そう もっと多くの自由が欲しいなら
親の信頼を得なければなりません
you have to gain your parents’ trust.
Earning their trust takes time.
信頼を得るには時間がかかります
But every time
you prove yourself responsible,
でも 責任ある行動を取るたびに
ゴールに近づいているのです
you get one step closer to your goal.
Some ways you can show
you are trustworthy are:
信頼できることを示すためには—
何度も言われなくても
家の手伝いをきちんとします
diligently completing your chores,
especially without being reminded;
managing your time wisely
自分で上手に時間を管理し
時間を守りましょう
and being punctual;
taking care of your things;
自分の持ち物を大切に扱います
showing that you can handle
money in a responsible way;
責任をもってお金を管理します
and following through
on the promises you make.
約束したなら守りましょう
もちろん 完ぺきな人はいません
Of course, nobody’s perfect.
So if you make a mistake,
it’s not the end of the world.
たとえ失敗しても
落ち込まないでください
聖書のヘブライ 13章18節に
あるように—
Follow the Bible’s advice
at Hebrews 13:18
“すべてのことにおいて正直に”
行動しましょう
to conduct yourself
“honestly in all things.”
Tell the truth
and be straightforward.
本当のことを隠さずに話してください
If you admit your mistake
and apologize,
間違いを認めて謝るなら—
your parents will see
that you are willing
to take responsibility
for your actions,
親はあなたの責任感や正直さを
高く評価するでしょう
and they’ll appreciate
your honesty.
But what if you feel
that despite your best efforts,
ベストを尽くしているのに—
親がなかなか自由を与えてくれないと
感じるときはどうですか？
your parents still aren’t giving
you enough freedom?
Don’t just get annoyed
イライラしても 親に話しましょう
—talk to them!
信頼してもらうために何が必要か
敬意をもって尋ねてみてください
Respectfully ask what they think
you need to do to earn their trust.
You may be surprised
to learn of some other areas
努力できる意外な点を
教えてもらえるかもしれません
where you can show
you’re responsible.
At 2 Corinthians 13:5,
the Bible says:
コリント第二 13章5節には—
“自分が……どんなものであるかを
絶えず吟味しなさい”とあります
“Keep proving what you . . . are.”
So you need to build up
a record of consistency.
つまり 信頼の記録を
積み上げていく必要があるのです
That way you’ll prove
you’re worthy of trust.
信頼できることを証明しましょう
Every step you take
brings you closer to your goal.
一歩一歩 ゴールに近づいて行きます
Of course, trust is much harder
to gain than it is to lose.
もちろん 信頼を失うのは簡単ですが
得るのはとても大変です
But the effort is worth it.
それでも 努力する価値があります
When your parents see you
working hard to earn their trust,
親は 信頼を得るために
努力しているあなたを見て—
they will likely be happy
to give you more freedom,
喜んで もっと自由を与えてくれるでしょう
and you’ll be another step closer
to becoming a responsible adult.
責任ある大人に
さらに近づくことができるのです